So to revisit then the solution that we built in the previous day and talk about the metrics.
그럼 전날 만든 솔루션을 다시 살펴보고 측정법에 대해 얘기해보죠
As I say, we've actually got very simple business centric metrics to gauge the performance and evaluate
말씀드렸듯이 아주 간단한 비즈니스 중심 지표가 있습니다 성과를 측정하고 결과를 평가하는
the performance of our results.
지표죠
It's quite simply the performance of the code.
코드의 성능이 중요하죠
How much faster did we make the code?
코드를 얼마나 빨리 만들었죠?
And obviously Claude 3.5 sonnet crushed it and and came through as the front runner, as the leader,
클로드 3도 있고요 5 소네트가 멋지게 해냈고 선두로 나섰습니다
followed by GPT four zero, which sometimes failed with the mission, but also sometimes succeeded and
그 뒤를 GPT 40이 따랐죠 임무에 실패할 때도 있었지만 성공할 때도 있었습니다 꽤 빠른
with a fairly fast solution.
해결책으로요
And then, unfortunately, Code Kwan did, as I say, a decent effort, but was not able ever to get
불행히도 코드 콴도 노력은 했지만 제대로 된 결과를 얻지 못했어요
the right results despite some attempts to force it through system prompts.
강제로 get을 입력하려 했지만요
Slightly cheating wasn't good enough.
살짝 속이는 거로는 부족했어요
Uh, so, you know, again, I do just want to point out that Quinn has 7 billion parameters and it's
다시 한번 말씀드리지만 퀸의 매개 변수는 70억 개예요 1조 개보다
closed source rivals way more than a trillion parameters.
훨씬 많은 비공개 소스의 라이벌이죠
So the very fact that it could do what it could do is incredibly impressive.
이런 일을 할 수 있다는 사실 자체가 정말 인상적이에요
And remember that aside from that, that cost of running it, um, the $0.80, I was paying an hour
그리고 운영 비용은 0달러라는 걸 기억하세요 80%면 결론으로 내려고
for it to be running as an inference end point.
1시간이나 냈고요
Aside from that, it is free.
그 외에는 무료예요
It's open source.
오픈 소스 소스예요
Uh, and so we're not paying API costs.
API 비용을 내지 않아요
And there are ways that you could run it on your local box, um, particularly if you have a GPU, uh,
로컬 박스에서 실행할 방법이 있습니다 특히 GPU가 있다면요
in which case, again, there's no cost other than the cost of running your box, the electricity.
이 경우 비용은 없어요 박스를 실행하는 비용과 전기 비용 외에는요
Uh, so it's a very impressive, uh, model.
아주 인상적인 모델이에요
It's it's it's frankly extraordinary that an open source model with only 7 billion parameters can do
그건 솔직히 정말 놀라워요 70억 매개 변수만 있는 오픈 소스 모델이 해당 코드를 파이 계산으로
things like converting that code to calculate pi.
변환하는 그런 일을 할 수 있다는 게요
So at this point, I want to introduce the challenges for you.
이 시점에서 여러분께 과제를 알려 드릴게요
And this week I've got a number of them and they are quite hard, but they'll be so fulfilling, so
이번 주에는 여러 가지를 준비했는데 꽤 어렵지만 정말 만족스럽고 뿌듯할 거예요
satisfying, that I want to encourage you more than ever to give this a shot.
그래서 그 어느 때보다 여러분께 도전해 보라고 권하고 싶어요
I do hope you have time.
시간이 있으면 좋겠네요
I've tried to keep this days lectures relatively brief to free up some time so you can do it.
오늘 강의는 상대적으로 짧게 하려고 했어요 여러분이 할 수 있도록 시간을 좀 내려고요
This will really solidify a lot of what we learned so far.
지금까지 배운 걸 확실히 보여줄 거예요
A couple of smaller things to tweak.
몇 가지만 수정하면 돼요
The solution we've already got.
이미 있는 해결책이죠
You can add Gemini into the closed source models so that the Gemini is you've got GPT for Claude and
제미니를 비공개 소스 모델에 추가할 수 있습니다. 제미니는 클로드와 제미니를 위한 GPT가
Gemini, and you can also add in more open source models.
있고 더 많은 오픈 소스 모델을 추가할 수 있죠
As I was suggesting, you can add in code Llama and Star Coder, and you could see whether or not you
제가 제안했던 것처럼 코드 라마와 별 코더를 추가할 수 있습니다 코드 젬마가 작동하도록
can force Code Gemma to work.
강제할 수 있는지 알 수 있죠
Um, maybe it can be convinced to not rewrite the random number generator by a series of aggressive
난수 발생기를 다시 쓰지 말라고 설득할 수 있을지도 몰라요 그런 일이 일어나지 않도록 공격적인
prompts to try and stop that happening.
프롬프트를 여러 개 던져서요
Uh, see if you have more luck than me.
나보다 운이 좋은지 보죠
If you do, then please, please push the code.
있다면 제발 코드를 눌러주세요
Let me see it.
어디 봐요
Let me include it and I'll share it with others.
다른 사람들과 공유할 거예요
And then we can all benefit from it.
그럼 우리 모두 이득을 볼 수 있죠
And that would be.
그게 바로 그거죠
Yeah.
네
Really terrific.
정말 멋져요
So give it a try and share your results.
그러니 한번 시도해 보고 결과를 공유해 주세요
But then.
근데요
But then I have three thorny challenges for you which is going to take your your abilities to generate
하지만 세 가지 가시 돋친 도전이 있어요 여러분의 능력을 이용해 코드를 생성해야 하죠
code.
한 단계 더 발전할 거예요
So here's some really great ideas.
좋은 아이디어가 있어요
One of them would be to write a coding tool that can automatically add comments or docstrings to your
그 중 하나는 코딩 도구를 작성하는 겁니다 코드에 자동으로 주석이나 docstrings을 추가하는
code, something that might be really useful.
거죠 아주 유용할 수도 있는 거죠
I know that there's some products out there that do it already, but it'd be great to do it yourself
이미 그렇게 하는 제품들이 있다는 걸 알지만 직접 해보시면 좋을 겁니다
and see it working and see whether code is good enough to do this for you.
작동하는 걸 보고 코드가 이걸 하기에 충분한지 보는 거죠
Uh, another would be a tool that can write unit tests.
다른 건 단위 테스트를 작성하는 도구죠
Uh, unit testing is something which is the bane of some of our lives.
단위 테스팅은 우리 삶의 골칫거리예요
Uh, it can be very grueling.
아주 힘들 수도 있어요
and sometimes unit tests can be very poorly written if all they're doing is just sort of replicating
때때로 단위 테스트는 아주 엉성하게 작성될 수 있어요. 그들이 하는 모든 것이 함수의 입력과 출력을
inputs and outputs of a function rather than doing something sensible.
복제하는 것이라면요. 합리적인 것을 하는 것보다요.
So see if you can use frontier models and maybe open source models to generate unit test cases for a
프론티어 모델과 오픈 소스 모델을 이용해 파이썬 특정 모듈을 위한 단위 테스트 케이스를 생성할
particular Python module.
수 있는지 보세요
And then finally, this is a really fun one.
마지막으로 정말 재미있는 거예요
And I've done this.
이것도 해 봤어요
So I have this myself just just for for entertainment value alone.
이건 그냥 오락용으로 제가 갖고 있는 거예요
And it's great.
정말 좋아요
It's great.
좋아요
And you should try it to write a code generator that writes code to make trading decisions for buying
모의 환경에서 주식을 사고팔기 위한 거래 결정을 내릴 코드를 작성하는
and selling equities in a simulated environment.
코드 생성기를 만들어 보세요
It's a bigger project, I realize.
더 큰 프로젝트인 건 알아요
But you could get you could take it baby steps at a time by just having it generate code.
하지만 Get은 한 번에 하나씩 할 수 있어요 코드 생성만으로요
You don't necessarily need the simulated environment.
시뮬레이션 환경이 꼭 필요한 건 아니에요
So you provide it with an API.
API 기능을 제공하죠
You could you could look for some of the common APIs that are available for looking up equity stock
일반적인 API를 찾아볼 수도 있어요 지분 주가를 알아보기 위해서요
Or you could just invent an API and just provide it in the prompt so that the model knows what methods
아니면 API를 발명해 프롬프트에 제공해 특정 날짜에 대한 체크메이트
it can call to get the price of a ticker on a particular date, and then have it generate functions
가격을 얻기 위해 어떤 방법을 호출할 수 있는지 모델이 알도록 할 수도 있죠 그런 다음 거래 결정을 수행하거나
that will carry out, buy or sell trading decisions.
구매, 판매하는 기능을 생성하게 하는 거죠
And yeah, I had terrific fun with this.
네, 정말 재미있었어요
I was able to build a ton of different trading signals, both using frontier models and open source
엄청나게 다양한 트레이딩 신호를 구축할 수 있었어요 프론티어 모델과 오픈 소스 모델을 사용해서요
One thing I will say is please, whatever you do, if you do this, do not actually use it to make trading
하나만 부탁할게요 뭘 하든, 하게 되더라도 그걸 거래 결정에 이용하진
decisions.
마세요
I strongly advise you not to use these sorts of models to make trading decisions.
이런 식으로 거래 결정을 내리지 말라고 강력히 권고할게요
In fact, if you try and ask frontier models to generate these methods, they'll do so, but they will
사실, 선구 모델에 이런 방법을 만들라고 요청하면 만들겠지만
warn you that it should not be used for real trading decisions under any circumstances.
어떤 상황에서든 실무 거래 결정에 사용하면 안 된다고 경고할 거예요
So consider that a stern warning.
엄중한 경고라고 생각하세요
Use this purely for your own enjoyment and to to see the capabilities involved, not for actually risking
순수하게 여러분의 즐거움을 위해 사용하세요 관련된 기능을 보고 싶으시다면 LM의 변덕에
fame and fortune on the whim of an LM, whether it's closed or open source.
명예와 부를 걸 필요는 없습니다 닫혀있든 오픈 소스든 간에요
But this is a great project.
하지만 이건 훌륭한 프로젝트예요
I'm sure you'll enjoy it.
마음에 드실 거예요
I might share my code if no one else does, but I you know, first of all, I put the challenge to you
아무도 제 코드를 공유하지 않는다면 전 할 수도 있어요 하지만 먼저 도전 과제를 드렸어요 여러분이 할
have a shot at doing it.
수 있는 기회요 Put
If you generate some trading signals, then I challenge you.
거래 신호를 보내면 도전하겠어요
I'll go head to head with you and see in a simulated environment only, of course, which of our different
당신과 직접 시뮬레이션 환경에서 살펴볼 겁니다 물론 가짜 시장에서
generated trading functions are able to make more more money in a fake market?
더 많은 돈을 벌 수 있는 다양한 거래 기능이 있을까요? HDP, DM
There you go.
여기요
That should be a really fun project for you, and I can't wait to see what people come up with.
재미있는 프로젝트가 될 거예요 다른 참가자들의 작품을 빨리 보고 싶네요
And with that, would you believe it?
그리고 또 있어요, 믿어지세요?
Would you believe this?
이게 믿어져요?
We have just reached the 50% point in this journey to to being a proficient LM Engineer.
숙련된 LM 엔지니어가 되기 위한 여정의 50% 지점에 도달했어요
You are half way there.
절반 남았어요
At least you're halfway there after you've done some of that homework and built some of those projects.
적어도 반은 온 거예요 숙제를 하고 프로젝트를 몇 개 완성하면요
Because that's, as I say, the most, the best way to learn is by doing.
가장 좋은 배우는 방법은 행동으로 배우는 거니까요
And so once you've done that, then you can pat yourself on the back and say you've got 50% of the way
일단 그렇게 하고 나면 스스로를 칭찬하며 50%는 성공했다고 말할 수
there.
있죠
And there is so much more to come next time we're going to be talking about rag Super Hot Topic, and
다음 시간에는 더 많은 이야기가 기다리고 있습니다 슈퍼 핫한 래그 토픽과 래그의 숨은 원대한
we're talking about the big idea behind Rag.
아이디어에 관해 이야기할 거예요
We're going to walk through the high level flow of adding expertise into your queries, and we're going
여러분의 쿼리에 전문 지식을 추가하는 높은 수준의 흐름을 살펴보겠습니다 그리고
to implement a toy version of Rag, a simple version without introducing these things called vector
Rag의 장난감 버전을 구현할 겁니다 벡터 데이터베이스라는 걸 도입하지
databases, which is the big, the big thinking behind Rag.
않는 간단한 버전으로요 Rag의 가장 큰 개념이죠
So I can't wait to get to all of that.
그래서 빨리 get it을 하고 싶어요.
Next week is going to be really, really exciting.
다음 주는 정말 재미있을 거예요
And again, one more time, a massive congratulations for being halfway on your journey to mastering
다시 한번 진심으로 축하드려요 림스를 지배하는 여정의 절반을 지나왔잖아요